人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  小舞
翻译 创行CFAUNB
翻译 送小孩
翻译 小熊嘟嘟
翻译 尼克白
翻译 泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 imok
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 崽猪
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第三集
是你  是你
You did this. You did this!
-我们现在就得走  -抓住他  抓住他
- We have to leave. - Take him! Take him!
他妻子呢
Where is his wife?
珊莎在哪里
Where's Sansa?
找到她  关闭城门
Find her. Bar the gates of the city.
封锁港口所有船只
Seize every ship in the harbor.
-她在哪里  -任何人不得离开君临
- Where is she?! - No one leaves the capital!
任何人
No one!
-上船  -我们去哪里
- Get in. - Where are we going?
安全的地方
Somewhere safe.
上去吧  小姐
Up you go, my lady.
您不会有事的
You'll be fine.
您比自己所知的更坚强
You're stronger than you know.
-贝里席大人  -叫我培提尔
- Lord Baelish? - Petyr.
你受伤了吗  小姐
Are you hurt, my lady?
很好  很好
Good. Good.
你一定受惊了  放心吧
I'm sure you've had quite a fright. Rest easy.
-最糟的已经过去了  -贝里席大人
- The worst is past. - Lord Baelish.
我保证过会把她安全送来
I promised I'd get her to you safely.
轻声些  我的朋友
Softly, my friend.
水上声音传得远
Voices carry over water.
我得回去了  趁还没人想起找我
I should get back before someone thinks to look for me.
先拿上你的报酬
First you'll want your pay.
-一万  对吧  -一万
- 10,000 was it? - 10,000.
等等
Wait!
你可不想给太后听见  是不是
You don't want the queen to hear, do you?
一千金袍子在搜捕你
1,000 gold cloaks are searching for you.
如果给他们抓到
And if they found you,
你猜他们会怎样处罚谋害国王的女孩
how do you think they would punish the girl who murdered the king?
-我没谋害任何人  -我知道  我知道
- I didn't murder anyone. - I know. I know.
可你必须承认自己嫌疑十足
But you must admit it looks suspicious.
国王处决了你父亲
The king who executed your father,
折磨你这些年
who tormented you for years,
而你从他遇害的现场逃逸
and you fled the scene of his murder.
你为什么杀他
Why did you kill him?
因为他是个酒鬼  蠢人
Because he was a drunk and a fool
我不信任愚蠢的酒鬼
and I don't trust drunk fools.
他救了我
He saved me.
他救你  小姐  他不过听命于我
Saved you? My lady, he followed my orders.
这都是我的安排  他只是为了金子
Every one of them. And he did it all for gold.
金钱买得一时安全
Money buys a man's silence for a time.
好箭可保一世平安
A bolt in the heart buys it forever.
他帮我是因为我救过他的命
He was helping me because I saved his life.
没错  他还送了你一条价值连城的项链
Yes, and he gave you a priceless necklace
他祖母的遗物
that once belonged to his grandmother.
霍拉德家族最后的传家宝
The last legacy of House Hollard.
我几周前叫人做的
I had it made a few weeks ago.
关于君临我教过你什么
What did I once tell you about the capital?
在这里我们都是骗子
We're all liars here.
来吧  小姐
Come, my lady.
我知道你今天很累了
I know you've had a difficult day.
你现在是安全的
But you're safe now.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
你在我身边是安全的
You're safe with me
我们乘船回家
and sailing home.
我还是王后吗
So am I the queen?
比你跟着蓝礼时名正言顺一点
More than you were with Renly.
要是乔佛里早全了礼数  跟你圆房再死
Less than you would have been if Joffrey had done you the courtesy
还能更名正言顺些
of consummating the marriage before dying.
反正现在也不是纠结这个问题的时候
In any case, this would not be an opportune moment to press the issue.
他用手抓着喉咙
Clawing at his own throat,
望着他母亲求助  真是可怕
looking to his mother to make it stop-- it was horrible.
世上可怕之事比比皆是
The world is overflowing with horrible things.
在死亡面前全都不值一提
But they're all a tray of cakes next to death.
你祖父死的时候  他们把尸体带回来给我
They brought me your grandfather's body when he died, you know?
让我去看
Made me look at it.
那是什么感觉
What was it like?
他们带我到停灵的大厅
They took me to the Great Hall and there he was.
那个我托付一生
The man I'd married
给他生下儿女的男人
and suffered to father my children.
那个在无尽的晚宴和乏味的聚会上
A great doughy lump I'd sat next to
坐在我身旁的软胖子
at endless dinners and tedious gatherings.
就在那里...
There he was...
躺在一张桌子上
lying on a table.
我的两任丈夫  一个偏好男色
One of my husbands preferred the company of men
一刀穿心毙命
and was stabbed through the heart.
另一个最爱折磨动物取乐
Another was happiest torturing animals
婚宴上中毒而死
and was poisoned at our wedding feast.
-我一定是受了诅咒  -胡说
- I must be cursed. - Nonsense.
你的处境如今明显好转
Your circumstances have improved markedly.
眼看他死去你或许不舒服
You may not have enjoyed watching him die,
可是我向你保证  看他死
but you enjoyed it more than you would have enjoyed
远比你嫁给他要过得舒服多了
being married to him, I can promise you that.
我本来是要当王后的
But I would have been the queen.
我们家族与兰尼斯特的联盟
Our alliance with the Lannisters
于我们仍有诸多不快
remains every bit as necessary to them
在他们则仍是务须维持
as it is unpleasant for us.
你应对乔佛里的手段很漂亮
You did wonderful work on Joffrey.
对付下一个应该更容易
The next one should be easier.
你哥哥死了
Your brother is dead.
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what that means?
我不是在套你话
I'm not trying to trick you.
意味着我会成为国王
It means I'll become king.
是的  你会成为国王
Yes, you will become king.
你认为自己会成为什么样的国王
What kind of king do you think you'll be?
好国王
A good king?
我也这样认为
Mm, I think so as well.
你有好国王该有的性子
You've got the right temperament for it.
但怎样才能成为好国王
But what makes a good king?
好国王最重要的品质是什么
What is a good king's single most important quality?
此时此地不适合谈这个
This is hardly the place or the time.
圣洁
Holiness?
"受神祝福的"贝勒圣洁
Baelor the Blessed was holy.
而且虔诚
And pious.
他建造了这座圣堂
He built this sept.
他还任命一个六岁男童为总主教
He also named a six-year-old boy high septon
因为他认为那男童可以施行神迹
because he thought the boy could work miracles.
他在春秋鼎盛之际断食而死
He ended up fasting himself into an early grave
因为食物来自俗世
because food was of this world
而俗世满是罪孽
and this world was sinful.
公正
Justice.
没错
Yeah.
一位好国王必须公正
A good king must be just.
奥里斯一世公正
Orys I was just.
所有人都为他的改革举措喝彩
Everyone applauded his reforms.
贵族和平民都拥护
Nobles and commoners alike.
但他也没公正多久
But he wasn't just for long.
不到一年就被他亲兄弟杀死在睡梦中
He was murdered in his sleep after less than a year by his own brother.
他真的公正吗
Was that truly just of him?
不谙世事  不辨忠奸
To abandon his subjects to an evil
害他的臣民落入魔掌
that he was too gullible to recognize?
-不  -不
- No. - No.
-力量呢  -不错
- What about strength? - Yes.
力量
Strength.
劳勃国王有力量
King Robert was strong.
他起义成功
He won the rebellion
推翻坦格利安王朝
and crushed the Targaryen dynasty.
在位十七年只出席了三次御前会议
And he attended three small council meetings in 17 years.
他整日狎妓  打猎  酗酒
He spent his time whoring and hunting and drinking
直到最后两样夺去他的性命
until the last two killed him.
我们现在有一位绝食而亡的国王
So, we have a man who starves himself to death,
一位任由亲兄弟弑君篡位的国王
a man who lets his own brother murder him,
一位以为赢得战争和统治国家是一回事的国王
and a man who thinks that winning and ruling are the same thing.
他们都缺少什么
What do they all lack?
-智慧  -对了
- Wisdom. - Yes!
智慧成就好国王
Wisdom is what makes a good king.
是的
Yes.
但什么是智慧呢
But what is wisdom? Hmm?
一个家财万贯  领土肥沃的家族
A house with great wealth and fertile lands
来寻求你的保护
asks you for your protection
以对抗另一个有着强大水军
against another house with a strong navy
某天可能起兵造反的家族
that could one day oppose you.
你怎么知道选择哪个更为明智呢
How do you know which choice is wise and which isn't?
你对国库  粮仓  船坞和士兵
You've any experience of treasuries and granaries
可有任何了解
or shipyards and soldiers?
-没有  -当然没有
- No. - No. Of course not.
明智的国王清楚自己知道什么不知道什么
A wise king knows what he knows and what he doesn't.
你还年轻
You're young.
明智的年轻国王要倚仗御前顾问
A wise young king listens to his counselors
听取他们的谏言  直到成年
and heeds their advice until he comes of age.
而最明智的国王
And the wisest kings
成年后依然听取他们谏言
continue to listen to them long afterwards.
你哥哥不是个明智的国王
Your brother was not a wise king.
你哥哥也不是个好国王
Your brother was not a good king.
如果他明智
If he had been,
也许就不会死了
perhaps he'd still be alive.
现在  作为国王  你要结婚
Now, as the king, you will have to marry.
你知道为什么吗
Do you understand why?
国王需要王后
A king needs a queen.
对  但是为什么
Yes, but why?
为了延续家族的血脉
To further the family line.
-你知道该怎么做吗  -知道
- Do you know how that happens? - Yes.
很好  有人给你详细讲过吗
Yes, but has anyone explained the details to you?
我想没有
I don't think so.
其实很简单
It's all relatively straightforward.
-你还好吗  -我没事
- How are you? - I'm all right.
是的  你不会有事
You are. You will be.
有我在
I'll see to that.
请让太后陛下与她的儿子独处片刻
Please give the queen a moment alone with her son.
-是  大人  -全都退下
- Yes, my lord. - All of you.
是提利昂干的
It was Tyrion.
他杀了我儿子
He killed him.
他说过要这么干
He told me he would.
"总有一天  当你自以为平安快活时
"A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
喜悦必将在你嘴里化成灰烬"
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth."
他就是这么对我说的
That's what he said to me.
你也看见了
You saw it.
你也看见小乔咽气前指着他
You saw Joff point at him just before he--
我不知道我看到了什么
I don't know what I saw.
为他报仇
Avenge him.
为我们的儿子报仇
Avenge our son.
杀了提利昂
Kill Tyrion.
提利昂是我弟弟
Tyrion's my brother.
也是你的弟弟
Our brother.
到时候会有审判  我们可以查出真相
There'll be a trial. We'll get to the truth of what happened.
我不需要审判
I don't want a trial.
他一有机会就会耍花招逃脱
He'll squirm his way to freedom given the chance.
我要他死
I want him dead.
求你了  詹姆
Please, Jaime.
一定要杀了他
You have to.
那可是我们的儿子
He was our son.
我们的宝贝儿子
Our baby boy.
你真是个可恶的女人
You're a hateful woman.
诸神为何让我爱上一个可恶的女人
Why have the gods made me love a hateful woman?
詹姆  别在这里  求你
Jaime, not here, please.
求你了
Please.
住手
Stop it.
-住手  快住手  -我不
- Stop it. Stop. - No.
快住手  住手
Stop it. Stop.
住手
Stop.
住手  不能这样
Stop. It's not right.
这样不好  这样不好
It's not right. It's not right.
我不管
I don't care.
-不要  -我不管
- Don't. - I don't care.
-不要  詹姆  不要  -我不管
- Don't. Jaime, don't. - I don't care.
快下雨了
Gonna rain soon.
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
我想应该在美人市集附近
Near Fairmarket, I think.
你想
You think?
你没有地图吗
You don't have a map?
-没有  我没地图  -也许我们得弄一张
- No, I don't have a map. - Maybe we should get one.
等你看到了卖地图的店子  我给你买
Just point out the next map shop you see and I'll buy you one.
离鹰巢城还有多远
How far is it to the Eyrie?
-很远  -你确定我们没走错方向吗
- Far. - And you're sure we're going the right way?
相信我  丫头  我也想尽快送你过去
Believe me, girl, I want you there as soon as I can.
拿上金子  走我自己的路
Get my gold, be on my way.
-你要去哪儿  -关你什么事
- On your way where? - Why do you care?
可能买张船票去狭海那边
Might book passage across the Narrow Sea.
当个佣兵
Fight as a sellsword.
次子团  也许吧  听起来挺适合我的
Second Sons, could be. Seems like a good fit for me.
我想去布拉佛斯看看
I'd like to see Braavos one day.
为什么是布拉佛斯
Why Braavos?
我有朋友在那里
I have friends there.
深表怀疑
I doubt it.
七神保佑你们
Seven blessings to you.
-你要干什么  -我干什么  这是我的地
- What do you want? - What do I want? This is my land.
既然我站在这儿  那就是我的地
If I'm standing on it, it's my land.
我们只是来这儿饮马  很快就走
We were just watering the horses. We'll be on our way.
原谅我父亲
Forgive my father.
他在战争中受伤了
He was wounded fighting in the war.
他不在时  我们屋子着火了  我母亲死了
Our cottage burned down while he was gone and my mother with it.
从那之后他性情大变
He's never been the same.
他为哪个家族作战
Which house did he fight for?
奔流城的徒利家
The Tullys of Riverrun.
暴风雨要来了
There's a storm coming.
你们今晚得找个屋子避雨
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.
谷仓里有新鲜干草
There's fresh hay in the barn.
萨莉炖兔子的手艺跟她妈妈以前一样好
And Sally here makes rabbit stew just like her mom used to do.
家里简陋得很  但我们非常欢迎
We don't have much, but any man that bled
为徒利家流血的人
for House Tully is welcome to it.
天父  请仁慈地评断
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy
宽容我等凡人的脆弱
accepting our human frailty.
圣母  请保佑庄稼丰收
We ask the Mother to bless our crops
让我们可以填饱肚子  招待来客
so we may feed ourselves and all who come to our door.
战士  请赋予我们勇气
We ask the Warrior to give us courage
平安度过战乱和动荡的岁月
in these days of strife and turmoil.
少女  请捍卫萨莉的贞洁
We ask the Maiden to protect Sally's virtue
让她免受恶徒玷污
to keep her from the clutches of depravity.
七个祖宗都要念一遍吗
You got to do all seven of the fuckers?
父亲
Father!
铁匠  请强健我们的双手和脊背
We ask the Smith to strengthen our hands and our backs
帮助我们完成必需的劳作
so we may finish the work required of us.
老妪  请指引我们
We ask the Crone to guide us
在黑暗的旅程中行进
on our journey from darkness to darkness.
陌客  今天晚上请不要
And we ask the Stranger not to kill us
无缘无故地把我们杀死在床上
in our beds tonight for no damn reason at all.
不客气了
I'm so sorry.
味道很棒
Really good.
-你在孪河城打过仗吗  -你管那叫打仗
- Did you fight at the Twins? - Call that a fight?
简直是屠杀牲畜
Slaughtering livestock more like.
人们管它叫血色婚礼
The Red Wedding they're calling it.
瓦德·佛雷犯下了渎神的恶行
Walder Frey committed sacrilege that day.
他跟史塔克家分食了面包和盐
He shared bread and salt with the Starks.
给了他们宾客权利
He offered them guest right.
宾客权利已经没什么意义了
Guest right don't mean much anymore.
对我来说意义重大
It means something to me.
诸神会为他们复仇的
The gods will have their vengeance.
佛雷会因此在七层地狱中受烈火焚烧
Frey will burn in the seventh hell for what he did.
霍斯特·徒利统治奔流城的时候可不是这样
Things were different when Hoster Tully ruled the Riverlands.
年景有好有坏  对谁都是一样
We had good years and bad years, same as anyone.
但我们很安全  现在换成了佛雷家
But we were safe. Now with the Freys,
强盗四处劫掠  抢走我们的食物和银子
raiders come plundering, steal our food, steal our silver.
我原本想把萨莉送去北境  到我兄弟那儿去
I was gonna send Sally north to stay with my brother,
但北境也好不到哪儿去  举国上下都乱套了
but the north's no better. The whole country's gone sour.
有麦酒吗
You got any ale?
怕是没有
Afraid not.
男人家里怎么能没有麦酒呢
How can a man not keep ale in his home?
你看起来很会使那把剑
You look like you could really swing that sword.
像是受过正规训练的战士
A real warrior with proper training.
强盗肯定不是你对手
Those raiders wouldn't stand a chance against you.
你们待到新月再走怎么样
How would it be if you stayed on till the new moon?
我需要人帮忙干农活
I could use a man to help with the farmwork.
萨莉也在尽力帮我
Sally does what she can,
但她连捆干草都搬不动
but she can't lift a bale of hay.
如果有贼人想来占便宜
And if any thieves came looking for easy pickings,
我敢打赌  他们一看到你就会吓跑
one look at you, I'd bet they'd run the other way.
无意冒犯
Meaning no offense.
你付多少钱
What'll you pay?
我没多少钱
I don't have much.
但我藏了点银子  没被强盗抢去
But I have hidden a bit of silver from the bandits.
你出力  我给钱  如何
Fair wages for fair work?
我出力  你给钱
Fair wages for fair work.
-你干了什么  -快备好马
- What did you do?! - Get your horse saddled.
-你之前说过你不是贼  -现在是了
- You told me you weren't a thief. - I wasn't.
他收留了我们  给我们吃的  你却...
He took us in. He fed us and you--
没错  他收留了我们  他是个好人
Aye, he took us in. He's a good man
他女儿做的炖菜味道很好
and his daughter makes a nice stew.
冬天一到  他们都得死
And they'll both be dead come winter.
-你怎么知道  -我当然知道
- You don't know that. - I do know it.
他太弱了  自身难保
He's weak. He can't protect himself.
冬天一到  他们都得死
They'll both be dead come winter.
死人用不着银子
Dead men don't need silver.
你是七国上下最坏的坏蛋
You're the worst shit in the Seven Kingdoms.
比我坏的人太多了
There's plenty worse than me.
我只是认清现实而已
I just understand the way things are.
史塔克家要再掉几颗脑袋你才能明白
How many Starks they got to behead before you figure it out?
强奸犯  强奸犯
Raper. Raper.
偷马贼
Horse thief.
排行老九的儿子
Ninth born son.
强奸犯
Raper.
贼  贼和强奸犯
Thief. Thief and raper.
瞧啊  杀手山姆
There he is, Sam the Slayer.
要去上你的野人妓女吗
Going to visit your wildling whore?
-她不是妓女  -不是吗
- She's not a whore. - No?
今晚赏她个铜板就知道了
Maybe I'll give her a copper tonight and find out.
他们都以为我在撒谎
They all think I'm lying.
撒什么谎
About what?
杀了异鬼
Killing the white walker.
你没撒谎
You're not lying.
我永远忘不了它嚎叫的声音
I'll never forget the way it screamed.
但只有你看到了
But you're the only one that saw it.
他们认为你就是个...
And they all think you're just a--
什么
A what?
野人
Well, a wildling.
我父亲很讨厌这个词
My father hated that word.
这确实算不得好词
It's not a very nice word, I suppose.
我不知道
I don't know.
不过野人听起来不太好惹  对吧
It makes me sound a bit dangerous, doesn't it?
说起来
So...
你还好吧
are you all right?
没人来烦你吧
No one bothering you?
总有人斜眼瞧我
I get a lot of looks.
我听到他们拿我开玩笑
I hear them making their jokes.
但没人碰过我  你是这意思吧
But no one's touched me if that's what you mean.
我有时会担心
I worry about it sometimes.
一直担心
All the time.
为什么担心
Why do you worry about it?
一百个男人  只有一个女人
100 men, one woman.
他们有别的事情要想
They've got other things to think about.
他们脑子里只想这个
That's the only thing they think about.
-别犯傻了  -我没犯傻
- You're being silly. - I'm not being silly.
一百个男人晚上睡不着觉脑子净想你了
There's 100 men lying awake at night picturing you.
那你呢
What about you?
我怎么了
What about me?
吉莉
Gilly?
我担心你啊
I worry about you.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢谢你担心我
For worrying about me.
我不知道你在这里是否安全
I don't know if you're safe here.
他们是我的弟兄
They're my brothers,
但在来这里之前  有人是贼
but some of them were thieves before they came here.
有人是强奸犯
Some of them were rapers.
你见过他们在你父亲堡垒里的作为
You saw what they did at your father's keep.
你想说什么
So what are you saying?
也许你在鼹鼠村更安全
Maybe you'd be safer in Mole's Town.
你厌烦我了吗
Are you bored of me?
厌烦你
Bored of you?
我
I...
我想保护你
I want to protect you.
我把这些拿给哈布
I'll get these to Hobb.
照看一下小山姆
Keep an eye on little Sam.
陛下
Your Grace.
你现在识字了  那上面写了什么
You're a literary man now. What do you make of that?
-乔佛里  -篡夺者乔佛里·拜拉席恩
- Joffrey? - The usurper Joffrey Baratheon.
我念着这句话  将水蛭扔进火里
I said those words when I tossed a leech into the fire.
吸满了私生子之血的水蛭
A leech filled with bastard blood.
你放走的那个私生子
A bastard you set free.
我眼前是大好机会
I am now faced with a great opportunity
却无力抓住
and I am powerless to take advantage of it.
我会为您找到军队  陛下
I will find you an army, Your Grace.
我日夜操劳...
I've been working day and night--
你有什么成果
What progress have you made?
我为您的复国大业召集了比兹伯利家族
I've rallied House Peasebury to your cause.
比兹伯利家族
House Peasebury.
-穆斯古德家族  -穆斯古德家族
- House Musgood. - House Musgood.
-海伊家族  -海伊家族
- And House Haigh. - House Haigh.
他们的人加起来还不够打劫一间膳房
They don't have enough men between them to raid a pantry.
不用局限于维斯特洛  陛下
Westeros is not the world, Your Grace.
我们应该去东方寻找船只和士兵
We need to look east for ships and men.
黄金团麾下有一万精兵
10,000 skilled soldiers fight for the Golden Company.
-黄金团  -他们从不毁约
- The Golden Company? - They've never broken a contract.
他们是佣兵
They're sellswords.
我们愿意用血魔法助您登上王座
We're willing to use blood magic to put you on the throne,
却不愿意花钱雇人打仗吗
but we're not willing to pay men to fight?
红袍女的魔法是真的
Now the Red Woman's magic is real.
她的预言和看到的幻象或许也是真的
Her visions and prophecies may be, too,
但我没听说过靠幻象和预言就能赢得战争
but I've never heard of visions and prophecies winning a war.
赢得战争的是士兵  上战场的士兵
Soldiers win wars. Soldiers on the ground.
战场可一点儿也不干净
It's dirty on the ground.
我们没有金子
We don't have any gold.
目前没有
Not yet.
如果我不宣扬正统
If I do not press my claim,
我的正统必将被遗忘
my claim will be forgotten.
我不会被记在别人著写的史书里
I will not become a page in someone else's history book.
我的时间不多了  戴佛斯爵士
I'm running out of time, Ser Davos.
这意味着你的时间不多了
Which means you're running out of time.
你迟到了
You're late.
抱歉  公主殿下
I'm sorry, Princess.
我以为你不来了
I thought you weren't coming.
御前首相无暇分身
The Hand of the King doesn't have much leisure time.
好首相不会把
You won't be a very good Hand
"骑士"念成"骑土"
if you see the word knight and say "Ka-nigit."
只有一次  好几周前了
That happened once, weeks ago.
真是有其父必有其女
You're your father's daughter, no mistake.
你们俩太狠了
Bloody relentless, the both of you.
今天是一本新书  有很多不好认的词
It's a new one today. Lots of tricky words.
但我觉得你能应付
But I think you can manage.
默读永远无法长进
You'll never read well if you move your lips.
孩子就是这样学习的
That's how children do it.
《布拉佛斯首席剑士
"The Life and Adventures of Elyo Grivas
埃里奥·格雷瓦斯传》
First Sword of Braavos."
谢谢鼓励
Thank you very much.
我喜欢这本  有很多比剑和海盗的情节
I like this one. It's full of sword fights and pirates.
你以前当过海盗
You were a pirate once.
不  我不是海盗  我是走私贩
No, I was never a pirate. I was a smuggler.
有什么区别
What's the difference?
如果你是个出名的走私贩
Well, if you're a famous smuggler,
证明你很失败
you're not doing it right.
我父亲说罪犯就是罪犯
My father says a criminal is a criminal.
你父亲不懂得分辨
Your father lacks an appreciation
坏人坏事的细微差别
of the finer points of bad behavior.
布拉佛斯人也是
So do the Braavosi.
-你去过布拉佛斯  -当然
- You've sailed to Braavos? - Of course.
差点被一位布拉佛斯首席剑士砍了头
Almost got beheaded by a First Sword of Braavos.
我试着向他解释
I tried to explain to him
海盗和走私贩的区别
the difference between pirates and smugglers,
但他与你的父亲一样
but he didn't seem any more
对两者的区别不是很感兴趣
interested in the distinction than your father.
也是  如果你为布拉佛斯的铁金库干活
I suppose if you work for the Iron Bank of Braavos
你的每一艘黄金驳船都价值连城
and each one of your gold barges is worth half a kingdom,
当然就不太关心这些小小的差异
you tend not to be overly concerned with the kind of distinction--
-为什么亲我  -我要你写封信
- What was that for? - I need you to write a message.
你应该自己写  趁机练习一下
You should write it yourself. It's good practice.
这信对我太重要了
It's too important for me.
我需要个聪明人来写  来吧
I need a smart person to do it. Go on.
维斯特洛唯一的真王史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
To the offices of the Iron Bank of Braavos
致布拉佛斯铁金库之负责人
from Stannis Baratheon the one true king of Westeros.
可你不是国王
But that's not you.
我要引起他们重视
I need to get their attention.
继续  写吧
Go on. Write.
他已经见多识广了  对吧
He's seen some adventures, hasn't he?
-可爱的小家伙  -谢谢
- Precious little thing. - Thank you.
-他叫什么  -山姆
- What's his name? - Sam.
好听
Lovely.
那是他父亲吗
That the daddy?
不是
No.
他的父亲在哪儿
Where's the daddy?
他死了
He's dead.
你从哪儿来
Oh. Where you from?
北边
North of here.
North of here?
你他妈是个野人
You a fucking wildling?
-只要管吃管住  -对
- Only room and board? - That's right.
她可以打扫  做饭
She'll clean and cook
照顾其他姑娘的孩子
and look after the other girls' babies.
我可以给她找别的活儿
Could find other work for her, too.
-不做别的  -有钱赚
- No other work. - There'd be money.
你可以分成
Give you a piece of it.
不做别的
No other work.
我保证一有空就过来看你
I promise to come back and visit whenever I can.
你在这里更安全
You'll be safer here.
在黑城堡谁来保护你  我吗
Who's gonna protect you at Castle Black? Me?
你在长城以北保护过我
You protected me north of the Wall.
这不一样
This is different.
他们都是守夜人兄弟
They're brothers of the Night's Watch
我不能横刀相向
and I can't just stab them in the back
也不能像在卡斯特家里那样一走了之
and I can't run away, which is what we did at Craster's.
你要相信我
You have to trust me.
这是最好的法子
It's for the best.
对你最好
Best for you.
吉莉
Oh, Gilly.
不要这样
Please don't.
真贪心
Greedy.
不想要吗
No?
恕我冒昧  您美丽动人
I'm sorry. You're lovely,
只是我向来品不得如此佳味
I just never acquired the taste.
你竟然说我的美人是道菜
You're calling my beauty an acquired taste?
不碍的  爱人  我的美味供你专享
That's quite all right, lover. It's more for you.
人生的损失呀
Your loss.
您都一样喜欢吗
You like them both the same?
-姑娘和小伙  -很吃惊吗
- Boys and girls? - Does that surprise you?
人人都有偏好
Everyone has a preference.
那么人人都错失了世间一半的愉悦
Then everyone is missing half the world's pleasure.
诸神造彼物  我心欢喜
The gods made that and it delights me.
诸神造此物
The gods made this
我心同样欢喜
and it delights me.
战事面前  我站在多恩一边
When it comes to war, I fight for Dorne.
但情事面前  我心无芥蒂
When it comes to love, I don't choose sides.
希望我到您这年纪也一样生龙活虎
I hope I have as much stamina when I'm your age.
你多大  二十五岁
What are you, 25?
黄毛孩子
Children.
若你幸运
Someday, if you're lucky,
有天醒来会发现自己垂垂老矣
you will wake up and realize you are old.
这丰满的屁股瘪下去
That pretty ass of yours will sag.
肚皮颓然松弛  夜夜深受背痛的苦楚
Your belly will grow soft and your back will ache in the night
鬓角华发渐生
and gray hairs will sprout from your ears.
没人还想要你
No one will want you anymore.
在那天到来之前  一定要操尽兴
Make sure you fucked your fill before that day.
那您呢
Did you?
他是堂堂多恩亲王
He is a prince of Dorne.
姑娘小伙们会排着队等他临幸
Girls and boys will line up
直到他死去那天
to fuck him till the day he dies.
他们全都得排在你后面
They will all have to line up behind you.
-奥柏伦亲王  -泰温公爵
- Prince Oberyn. - Lord Tywin.
能否单独谈谈
May we have the room?
随时召唤我  爱人
Call my name if you need me, lover.
请坐吧
Would you like to sit?
不了  多谢
No, thank you.
来点酒
Some wine?
不了  多谢
No, thank you.
-你外孙的事  我深感遗憾  -是吗
- I'm sorry about your grandson. - Are you?
我认为孩子不应为父亲的罪行担责
I don't believe that a child is responsible for the sins of his father.
遑论外祖父的
Or his grandfather.
这种死法太惨
An awful way to die.
怎么个死法
Which way is that?
泰温公爵  你这是审问我吗
Are you interrogating me, Lord Tywin?
有人说国王是噎死的
Some believe the king choked.
有人说天空是蓝色  因为我们住在
Some believe the sky is blue because we live
蓝眼巨人的眼睛里
inside the eye of a blue-eyed giant.
国王是被毒杀的
The king was poisoned.
听说你在学城研习过毒药
I hear you studied poisons at the Citadel.
正是  所以我知道
I did. This is why I know.
而你对我家族的仇恨也是尽人皆知
Your hatred for my family is rather well known.
你这样的用毒高手刚到王城
You arrive at the capital, an expert in poisoning,
几天后我外孙便被毒杀
some days later my grandson dies of poisoning.
着实让人起疑
Rather suspicious.
那为何还不把我关进地牢呢
Why haven't you thrown me in a dungeon?
你初来那日  曾在这家妓院
You spoke with Tyrion in this very brothel
与提利昂会面
on the day that you arrived.
你们谈了什么
What did you discuss?
你是说我们合谋弑君
You think we conspired together?
你们谈了什么
What did you discuss?
我姐姐的死
The death of my sister.
你认为罪责在我
For which you blame me.
她被魔山先奸后杀
She was raped and murdered by the Mountain.
魔山是奉你的命令行事
The Mountain follows your orders.
我当然要怪在你头上
Of course I blame you.
我现在手无寸铁  未带护卫
Here I stand unarmed, unguarded.
是否性命堪虞
Should I be concerned?
你敢手无寸铁  不带护卫就进来
You are unarmed and unguarded
是因为你了解我的为人
because you know me better than that.
我是明白人
I am a man of reason.
我要是今天割你喉咙
If I cut your throat today,
明天就会被五马分尸
I will be drawn and quartered tomorrow.
战场无情  下人所犯的罪行
Men at war commit all kinds of crimes
统帅也未必知晓
without their superiors' knowledge.
这么说你认为自己与伊莉亚的死无关
So you deny involvement in Elia's murder?
毫不相关
Categorically.
我要见魔山
I would like to speak with the Mountain.
他肯定乐意见你
I'm sure he would enjoy speaking with you.
等到见了面  他怕是乐不起来了
He might not enjoy it as much as he thinks he would.
我可以安排你们会面
I could arrange for this meeting.
但你要回报
But you want something in return.
我儿子的审判快要开始了
There will be a trial for my son.
根据习俗
And as custom dictates,
须有三名法官方可开审
three judges will render a verdict.
我来主持
I will preside.
梅斯·提利尔是第二法官
Mace Tyrell will serve as the second judge.
我想请你担任第三法官
I would like you to be the third.
为何
Why?
不久前  提利尔家族还拥护蓝礼·拜拉席恩
Not long ago, the Tyrells sided with Renly Baratheon.
公然与王权为敌
Declared themselves enemies of the throne.
现在他们是我们最坚定的盟友
Now they are our strongest allies.
你让提利尔家的丫头当了王后
Well, you made the Tyrell girl a queen.
却让我做审判你儿子的法官  不怎么诱人呢
Asking me to judge at your son's trial isn't quite as tempting.
我还要邀你参议国事
I will also invite you to sit on the small council
成为新王的御前顾问
to serve as one of the new king's principal advisors.
没想到你如此看重多恩  泰温公爵
I never realized you had such respect for Dorne, Lord Tywin.
少了多恩  七大王国便名不副实
We are not the Seven Kingdoms until Dorne returns to the fold.
国王驾崩  葛雷乔伊家起兵叛乱
The king is dead. The Greyjoys are in open rebellion.
野人大军攻向绝境长城
A wildling army marches on the Wall.
远在东方  坦格利安家的孤女养了三条龙
And in the East, a Targaryen girl has three dragons.
不用多久  她就会打起维斯特洛的主意
Before long, she will turn her eyes to Westeros.
只有多恩人顽强抵御了
Only the Dornish managed to resist
伊耿·坦格利安和他的巨龙
Aegon Targaryen and his dragons.
你是说你需要我们
You're saying you need us?
你能承认这点一定相当不易
That must be hard for you to admit.
我们需要对方
We need each other.
你帮我制裁谋害国王的凶手
You help me serve justice to the king's assassins
我就帮你为伊莉亚主持公道
and I will help you serve justice to Elia's.
波德瑞克
Podrick.
这里太臭  实在抱歉
Apologies for the stench.
我本来给您带了酒  大人
I brought you some wine, my lord,
但被他们搜走了
but they took it from me.
你尽力了
A noble effort.
不过他们没搜到蜡烛
They didn't find the candles, though.
羽毛笔  羊皮纸
A quill, some parchment,
鸭肉香肠  杏仁
duck sausage, almonds,
还有硬奶酪
and some hard cheese.
你真是个好小子
You're a good lad.
有雪伊的消息吗
Any word of Shae?
杳无音信  大人
I've heard nothing, my lord.
这应该是好事
I suppose that's a good thing.
外头的人是怎么说我的
What are they saying about me out there?
您将在两周后接受审判
You're to stand trial in a fortnight
罪名是弑君
for murdering the king.
你相信是我杀了乔佛里吗
Do you believe I murdered Joffrey?
我不信  大人
No, my lord.
您没杀他吧
You didn't?
没有  当然没有
No. Gods, no.
没有他  世界当然更美好
The world is a better place without him,
但我和他的死毫不相干
but I had nothing to do with it.
我倒是觉得
I would like to think
如果我要刺杀王室成员
if I were arranging a royal assassination,
至少不能在国王死的时候
I'd plan it in such a way that I wouldn't be standing there
傻站在当场发呆
gawking like a fool when the king died.
两周后受审
Trial in a fortnight.
他们有没有宣布法官的人选
Have they announced the judges yet?
-您父亲  -这是自然
- Your father. - Of course.
梅斯·提利尔
Mace Tyrell.
唯我父亲马首是瞻的家伙
Who will vote exactly as my father tells him to vote.
以及多恩的奥柏伦亲王
And Prince Oberyn of Dorne.
奥柏伦
Oberyn?
我父亲这点真叫人佩服
Give it to my father.
家族惨剧也会成为他谋划的契机
He never fails to take advantage of a family tragedy.
您可以告诉我一些名字  大人
I'm supposed to get a list of names from you, my lord.
凡是能为您作证的人都行
Anyone who might testify on your behalf.
原来我还可以传召证人
Oh, I can call my own witnesses?
他们还真大方
How generous of them.
那好  我妻子  珊莎
Very well, my wife. Sansa.
大人  她不见了
My lord, she's gone.
-不见了  -婚礼后就再没人见过她
- Gone? - No one's seen her since the wedding.
您是不是认为她...
You don't think she...
没人比珊莎更有理由杀死乔佛里
No one had more cause to kill Joffrey than Sansa,
但那女孩可不是当杀手的料
but the girl is no assassin.
杀害国王的人还希望我因此掉脑袋
Whoever killed the king wanted me to lose my head for it.
再加上我妻子的失踪
And with my wife's disappearance,
使得我的罪名确凿无疑
it makes me seem that much more guilty.
-波德瑞克  -请吩咐  大人
- Podrick. - Yes, my lord?
-他们会跟踪你  -谁
- They'll be following you now. - Who will?
我不知道  就是他们  居心不良的人
I don't know. They. They. The ominous they.
不知是男是女的幕后黑手  我父亲
The man pulling the strings. Or woman. My father.
或许对他而言  乔佛里太过任性妄为
Maybe Joffrey was too much work for him.
而乖孩子托曼更容易控制
Sweet Tommen will be so much easier to handle.
每次只要我有什么麻烦
Whenever something bad happens to me,
我老姐肯定脱不了干系
I assume it's my sister that had a hand in it.
可瑟曦纵有千般不好
But say what you will of Cersei,
她爱自己的孩子
she loves her children.
她是唯一一个
She is the only one
我敢肯定和这次谋杀毫不相干的人
I'm certain had nothing to do with this murder.
这真是君临唯一一起与她无关的谋杀
Which makes it unique as King's Landing murders go.
还有别的证人吗  大人
Any other witnesses, my lord?
如果瓦里斯的胆儿够大  他也可以替我担保
Varys could vouch for me if he dared.
他已经是太后的传召证人了
He's already been called as a witness for the queen.
我早该想到了
Of course.
把波隆找来  我有活儿给他干
Fetch Bronn. I have a job for him.
我已经问过了  大人
I've already asked, my lord.
-他们不准他见您  -为什么
- They won't let him see you. - Why not?
他们说他是个杀手  而且和您关系密切
They say he's a known cutthroat and your close associate.
他也在接受调查
He's under investigation himself.
我老哥呢  他们好歹让我见见詹姆吧
And my brother? Will they at least allow me to see Jaime?
我去问  大人
I'll ask, my lord.
还有件事  大人
There's something else, my lord.
有个我不认识的人
A man, I didn't know his face,
他来问我能不能出庭指证您
he came to ask if I'd testify against you.
如果我告诉法官您买过一种叫扼死者的毒药
Said I'd be named Ser Podrick Payne
就能成为波德瑞克·派恩爵士
if I told the judges you'd bought a poison called the Strangler.
波德瑞克·派恩爵士
Ser Podrick Payne?
这头衔挺好听  你是怎么跟他说的
Has a nice ring to it. What did you tell him?
我什么都没说  大人
I didn't tell them anything, my lord.
你打算接受他们的条件吗
Are you going to accept their offer?
大人
My lord.
指证我可不是简单的提议
Testifying against me wasn't a suggestion.
他们要是发现软的不行
If they can't tempt you with honey,
就会对你来硬的
they'll choose something less sweet.
您向来待我不薄  大人
You've been good to me, my lord.
波德  两周后就要进行审判
Pod, the trial's in a fortnight.
他们在此之前要得到你的答复
They'll want an answer before that.
我已经答复过他们了  大人
I already gave them an answer, my lord.
我不准你因我而死
I will not have you dying on my behalf.
你听清了吗
Do you hear me?
如果我到时候免不了要上刑场
If I have to take that long walk to the executioner's block,
可不希望看到你的人头先挂了上去
I don't want to see your head already mounted.
-大人  -波德  我是在命令你
- My lord. - Pod, I am giving you an order.
去找我老哥  就说我要见他
Go and find my brother. Tell him I need him.
趁现在还来得及  快些离开君临
And get yourself out of King's Landing before it's too late.
波德
Pod!
在此别过
This is farewell.
别了  大人
Farewell, my lord.
波德
Pod.
世上从无你这般忠心的侍从
There has never lived a more loyal squire.
母亲说该吃饭了
Mother says it's time to eat.
她煮了什么  等等  让我猜猜
What's she got boiling? Wait. Wait. Let me guess.
-土豆  -土豆
- Potatoes. - Potatoes.
没人比你母亲更会煮土豆了  她...
Well, no one boils a potato better than your mom. She got--
是野人
The wildlings!
盖蒙
Guymon!
躲起来
Hide.
快躲起来
Hide!
-你知道怎么去黑城堡吗  -知道  知道
- You know how to get to Castle Black? - Yes. Yes.
那是你爸妈吗
Those your parents?
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
我要吃了他们
I'm going to eat them.
听到了吗
Do you hear me?
我要吃掉你死去的妈妈
I'm going to eat your dead mama
还要吃掉你死去的爸爸
and I'm going to eat your dead papa.
你去告诉黑城堡的乌鸦
Go tell the crows at Castle Black.
必须教训教训他们
We need to teach them a lesson
叫他们知道我们的手段
about the way we deal with their kind.
-是  -是
- Aye! - Aye!
从长城上扔几十条割了喉咙的尸体下去
Three dozen bodies with slit throats tossed off the top of the Wall.
-他们没准就学乖了  -对头
- Seems like that would be a good lesson. - Aye!
如果我们出兵追击  那便正中他们下怀
If we go after them, we'll be giving them what they want.
他们就希望引我们出击  一口一口啃掉我们
They want to draw us out, pick us off a few at a time.
我们不过一百来人
We have just over 100 men.
这还算上了事务官和工匠
And that's including stewards and builders.
还有我  一个人都损失不起
And me. We can't afford to lose a single man.
我们必须牢记最重要的责任
We must remember our first responsibility.
我们是长城上的守卫
We are the watchers on the Wall.
可我们必须想办法保护他们
There's got to be a way to protect them.
你最受百姓拥戴  雪诺大人
You're a champion of the common people, Lord Snow.
你怎么看派普兄弟的意见
What do you say to Brother Pyp's proposition?
曼斯·雷德大军压境
Mance Rayder is coming.
如果野人突破了长城
If the wildlings breach the Wall,
势必沿途烧杀掳掠  一路风卷残云
they'll roll over everything and everyone for 1,000 miles
千里之内没有一支像样的军队拦得住
before they reach an army that can stop them.
我们必须加固黑城堡
We need to shore up Castle Black
我们必须守住长城
and we need to defend the Wall.
这是我们的职责
That is our job.
游骑兵归来
Rangers returning.
快去帮他
Help him.
还以为你早变蓝眼睛了
Thought you'd have blue eyes by now.
怎么这么久才回来
What took you so long?
-我们身不由己  -为什么
- We were held up. - By what?
因为铁链子
Chains.
卡斯特堡垒里的叛徒拿我们当座上宾
We were guests of the mutineers at Craster's Keep.
-叛徒没走吗  -他们哪儿都不去
- And the mutineers stayed? - They're not going anywhere.
卡斯特的粮食和老婆都归他们了
They've got Craster's food and his wives.
可怜的姑娘们
Poor girls.
还不如老爹在世的时候呢
Never thought they'd miss their daddy.
现在那边卡尔是头儿
Karl's running things now.
就是他把刀插进卡斯特的嘴
He's the one who put a knife through Craster's mouth.
我们必须赶到北边杀了他们
We need to ride north and kill them all.
这事刚才已经否了  小子
We just went over this, boy.
-以后再制裁他们  -这跟制裁叛徒没关系
- Justice can wait. - It's not about justice.
我当时告诉野人  黑城堡有上千人驻守
I told the wildlings we had over 1,000 men at Castle Black alone.
卡尔他们知道我们的底细
Karl and the others know the truth as well as we do.
你觉得等野人一颗一颗拔他们的指甲时
How long do you think they'll keep that information to themselves
这个秘密能在他们嘴里守多久
when the wildlings are peeling their fingernails off?
曼斯的实力足以打垮我们  只是他还不知道
Mance has all he needs to crush us, he just doesn't know it yet.
等他找到了那些叛徒  一切都明白了
As soon as he gets his hands on them, he will.
到时候他必定全力攻来
Then he'll throw his full strength at us.
就算我们每人能杀掉一百个野人
And even if every one of us kills 100 wildlings,
也还是挡不住他们的进攻
there's still not a thing we can do to stop them.
我怕是杀不了一百个野人
I don't think I can kill 100 wildlings.
他们要进攻吗
Are they attacking?
一个骑兵
A single rider.
弥林的冠军
A champion of Meereen.
他们希望您派出我方的冠军迎战他
They want you to send your own champion against him.
他这是做什么
What is he doing?
我看他是要...
I believe he means to...
他说我们军队的男人缺了男人的东西
He says that we're an army of men without man parts.
他说您根本不是女人  而是一个...
He claims you are no woman at all, but a man who...
命根子缩在屁眼里的男人
hides his cock in his own asshole.
不必理会毫无意义的挑衅之辞  陛下
Ignore him, Your Grace. These are meaningless words.
若是我们要争取的半数民众
They're not meaningless if half the city
都在听的挑衅之辞  那就不能说毫无意义
you intend to take is listening to them.
我有话对弥林人民说
I have something to say to the people of Meereen.
不过  先要让这家伙闭嘴
First, I will need this one to be quiet.
我可有迎战的冠军
Do I have a champion?
请赐我这个荣誉  龙之母
我绝不辜负您
你是无垢者的指挥官
我不能拿你冒险
陛下  论单打独斗这世上数我最在行
Your Grace, I've won more single combats than any man alive.
所以你更应当留在我身边
Which is why you must remain by my side.
我在您身边的时间最长  卡丽熙
I've been by your side longer than any of them, Khaleesi.
今日让我为您出战
Let me stand for you today as well.
你是我最信任的顾问
You are my most trusted advisor,
最器重的将领  最珍视的朋友
my most valued general, and my dearest friend.
我不能赌上你的性命
I will not gamble with your life.
我最晚加入您麾下
I was the last to join your army.
我不是将领  不是女王铁卫
I'm not your general or a member of your Queensguard
也不是无垢者的指挥官
or the commander of your Unsullied.
我母亲是妓女  我从尘埃中来
My mother was a whore. I come from nothing.
不久以后  也将回尘埃中去
And before long, I will return to nothing.
让我为您杀掉那人
Let me kill this man for you.
很好
Very well.
你的观众可不少
You have quite an audience.
要让他们大开眼界
Make it worth their while.
他很勇敢  陛下
He is very brave, Your Grace.
是的  全城人都在见证这场较量的胜负
Yes, win or lose, as long as the whole city is watching.
你真的不用骑马
You sure you don't want a horse?
为什么要骑马
Why would I want a horse?
马的速度比人快
Horses are faster than men.
马比人笨
Horses are dumber than men.
我乃风暴降生丹妮莉丝
你们的主人或许对你们说了我的谎话
或许什么都没说
无所谓
我对他们无话可说
我只对你们说
起先  我去了阿斯塔波
阿斯塔波的奴隶
如今站在我身后
自由了
接着我去了渊凯
渊凯的奴隶
也站在我身后
自由了
现在我来弥林了
我不是你们的敌人
你们的敌人在你们身边
你们的敌人偷窃和杀害你们的孩子
你们的敌人只会锁住你们  虐待你们
奴役你们
我不是来奴役你们的
我来给你们选择
我还要制裁你们的敌人
上前
放